なんば　むった
(南波六太)おっと…おわっ！
何やってんだよ…
中で着替えでもしてんのか？
What's that guy doing?
Is he changing in there?
あっ 宇宙飛行士だ！
It's an astronaut!
Nah, an astronaut wouldn't be walking around with a pug.
ちげ～よ！宇宙飛行士が
パグ連れてるかよ｡➡
コスプレだ コスプレ｡
It's just a guy in a costume.
I'm too early...
《早く…来すぎた…》
《みんな 早く来て！》
Guys, hurry up...
Space Brothers
I can no longer remember
what I tried to forget
When I peeked through the telescope
I realized that our world is tiny
It was a picture of infinity
It's not a one-time thing
We'll walk together
Once we've passed the clouds,
we will hold the world between our fingers
and keep what we lost in mind
#46 Number One Restless Guy
(せりか)あ～おいしい…｡
This is so good...
ホレッ オトモダチさんたちも
たんと食べや｡
Come now, please help yourselves.
食べな おっきなれへんでぇ｡
You should eat more, so you grow big.
いやぁ～いつ見ても すごいなぁ
せりかん家の食卓は｡
Man, dinner at Serika's is always amazing.
いとう
伊東家の食卓…｡
Dinner with the Itous...
伊東家は先祖代々
これがノーマルや｡
For generations, this is how an Itou family dinner has looked.
マジッすか!?
せや｡
For real?
You bet.
すきま
｢テーブルの隙間は心の隙間｣やて
よう言うやろ！
You know how they say that an empty table is the sign of an empty heart?
Right?
言わんか？
ハハハッ 満たしていこ｡
Eat your hearts out.
Look.
これ 目ぇつぶってても
なん
もん
何かの食べ物には当たるからな｡
I can tell what's what, even with my eyes closed.
It's an Itou family trick.
ホレ！ある意味
伊東家のウラ技やろ｡
(まちこ)みんな ありがとね
せりかのために｡
Thank you for coming to send Serika off.
しばらく会えなくなるんで｡
るんで｡
You don't need to thank us.
We won't get to see her for a while.
Exactly.
Thanks.
ありがと｡フフフ…｡
さみしなるな～アメリカかぁ…｡
It'll be lonely in the house.
America, huh?
りんぺい
《凜平…➡
Rinpei...
Seri's going to America for training.
せりちゃん とうとう
アメリカで訓練やで｡➡
To become an astronaut.
宇宙飛行士になるんやで》
よう ここまで頑張ったなぁ｡
You've worked hard to make it this far.
You've done a wonderful job, Seri.
偉いわ せりちゃん
偉いわぁ｡
A wonderful job.
ちょっと…
まだ これからだよ おばあちゃん｡
Wait... I'm just starting out, Grandma.
頑張ってね せりか｡
Do the best you can, Serika.
Yeah.
Serika, good morning.
きたむら
(北村)せりかちゃん おはよ～！
えな
あ～ 絵名ちゃん！
Oh!
Ena!
(ｵｰｽｹ)うわ 懐かし！
(ｷｸｵ)ウソつけ お前！
(直樹)ぜって～覚えてないだろ｡
Whoa, this brings back memories!
Don't lie!
You don't remember this?
[VTR](赤ちゃん)あぶ～あぶぶ…｡
Is she holding Oosuke?
(北村父)だっこされてんの
オースケか？
(直樹)ねえちゃん 変わらね～｡
Sis looks just the same.
(北村父)絵名は この頃から
面倒見がいいな｡
From a young age, Ena was responsible.
Kikuo's nose is covered in snot.
(直樹)うわっ キクオ
鼻カピカピじゃん｡
Wait, that's me?
(ｷｸｵ)えっ これ俺!?
(北村母)そうだよ あんたよ！
Yes, that's you.
Huh?
(ｵｰｽｹ)頭 悪そう キク兄｡
You look pretty stupid.
You all look stupid to me.
みんな
似たようなもんだな こりゃ｡
絵名のおかげで ほんと
子育てが楽だったよ 母ちゃん｡
Thanks to Ena, I had an easy time raising the rest of you kids.
They still act like children, though...
今でも彼らは
子供みたいだけどね｡
I know what you mean.
そうだわねぇ｡
Hey, Kei!
ねえ ケイちゃん
こっち来て座りなよ｡
Come and sit down.
(ケイ)うん もうちょっとで
できるから｡
Mm, I'm almost done.
最近 よく手伝ってくれるんだよ｡
Recently, she's been helping out a lot.
プハーッ！
きょうだい
４人のやかましい弟妹を
手なずけた絵名だ｡
You helped to raise four noisy siblings, Ena.
You shouldn't have any trouble working with four astronauts.
４人の宇宙飛行士が相手でも
余裕だろう｡
誰がやかましいって？
父ちゃん｡
I'm not noisy, Dad.
Don't lump me in with my stupid brothers.
兄さんたちと一緒にしないでよ｡
Right?
ガハハハ！聞こえたか｡
Think they heard that?
そりゃ聞こえるわ 大きな声で｡
It was certainly loud enough.
You do realize that the astronaut candidates represent all of Japan?
言っとくけど
宇宙飛行士 日本代表だよ｡
The other astronauts are far more responsible than I am.
みんな私なんかより めちゃくちゃ
しっかりしてるんだからね｡➡
見習ってほしいよ
ウチの たるんだ弟どもにも｡
I wish my brothers would follow their example.
たるんでるぞ キクオ｡
髪を切れ！
Pull it together Kikuo. Cut your hair.
俺か？オースケなんか
プー太郎だろ｡
Me?
Oosuke's the unemployed one.
But Naoki slouches the most.
でも 直樹兄ちゃんが
一番 猫背だよ｡
(直樹)それ 全くカンケーない｡
How is that even relevant?
ケイちゃんが作ったの？
Did you make this Salisbury steak?
おいしい！お店の味みたい｡➡
It's delicious! As good as restaurant food...
What recipe did you use?
どうやって作ったの？
(ケイ)合格って聞いた時さ…
父ちゃん 泣いてた｡
When he heard you'd passed,
Dad cried.
Really?
(北村)ホントに!?
まるで お姉ちゃんが
どっかの嫁に行くみたいだったよ｡
He was acting like you were getting married off.
Kei, you really seem to have matured since I last saw you.
ケイちゃん 久しぶりに会ったら
なんか ちょっと➡
大人っぽくなったんじゃない？
そりゃそ～か…１９だし｡
I guess that makes sense.
You're already nineteen.
でも｢女っぽくね～｣って
特にキク兄が うるさいよ｡➡
But apparently, I'm not feminine enough.
Kikuo's always on my case.
あんな おとこどもの
下に生まれた 宿命かな｡アハハ｡➡
I guess I've been doomed ever since I was born after those brothers.
And then, with Kei, I also have a gender-neutral name.
名前も｢ケイ｣とか
どっちか わかりにくいし｡
おやじ
あ～あ 名付けた親父も悪いな｡
I guess Dad's to blame for naming me that.
でも｢ケイ｣って名前
カワイイと思うけどな｡
But the name Kei is pretty cool.
え～っ!? だけど
しりとりなんかで名前決める!?
But isn't using shiritori to name your kids kind of strange?
Ena, Naoki, Kikuo, Oosuke, Kei.
エナ･ナオキ･
キクオ･オースケ･ケイ｡
They didn't spend much time thinking them up.
絶対 テキトーだよ これ｡
すっごく合ってるよ
｢ケイ｣って名前 ケイちゃんに｡
I think the name Kei suits you.
何それ!? 何か変！
What do you mean?
You're acting weird!
うん そうかも｡
Yeah, I am.
(ケイ)ねえ お姉ちゃん…➡
Hey, Sis...
自分の将来ってさ
ど～やって決めたの？
How are you supposed to decide your future?
(北村)悩んでんの？
Are you having trouble?
(ケイ)ん～ だってさ➡
Well, I don't know what I want to become.
何になりたいとか
よく分かんないよ｡
(北村)そうだね…｡じゃあ…➡
I see...
In that case,
｢できるようになりたい事｣なら
どうよ？
is there anything that you wish you could do?
(北村)例えば ピアノ弾けるように
なりたいとか…｡
For instance, would you like to play the piano?
(ケイ)ああ～いいね なりたい｡
Oh...
Sure, I would.
英会話をマスターしたいとか…｡
Do you wish you could hold conversations in English?
(ケイ)うん マスターしたい｡
Yep, I sure do.
そ～いうのでさ 時間も忘れて
続けられるようなものが➡
You just need
to find the one thing interesting enough to make you lose track of time.
１コでも見つかればいいよね｡
One thing...
(ケイ)１コか…｡
《そっか １コでもいいのか》
Oh, I only need one thing...
Sorry, Sis.
(ケイ)ごめんね お姉ちゃん 明日
空港まで送りに行けなくて｡
I won't be able to go to the airport with you tomorrow.
いいよいいよ 遠いんだから｡
That's okay... It's a long trip.
Yeah.
訓練 頑張ってね！
Good luck with your training!
ありがと！行ってくるよ｡
Thanks, I'm off.
Wait a sec, Sis!
ちょっと待って お姉ちゃん！
１コあった｡
I thought of something.
私 お姉ちゃんより おいしい料理
作れるようになりたいんだ｡
I want to become a better cook than you.
(北村)ケイちゃん さっきの
ハンバーグ あれさ…➡
Kei, remember the Salisbury steak you made for dinner?
お金 取れるよ｡フフッ｡
People would pay to eat that.
(北村)２年かぁ～｡
長い旅になるねぇ｡
Two years...
This will be a long trip.
ヨロシクね せりかちゃん｡
Glad to be with you, Serika.
こちらこそ ど～ぞ よろしく｡
Same here.
I'm glad we're together.
こまち
あ！小町さん 発見！
Oh!
There's Komachi.
実際 無重力を体験して
どんな感じでした？
What does it feel like to be weightless?
あの～
月って どうだったの？
Um, what was the moon like?
Oh, well, let's see...
《まだ行ってね～し…》
I haven't been there yet.
サインちょ～だい｡
Can I have your autograph?
A-Autograph?
サ…サイン!?
よ よ～し！ＯＫ ＯＫ！
O-Okay, you got it!
《ど～しよ…まだサインなんて
考えてね～よ！》
What do I do? I haven't come up with an autograph yet.
《普通に名前書いたんじゃ
カッコ悪いしな…➡
And it would be pretty lame if I just wrote my name.
Guess I'll just scribble something fancy looking.
あ～ なんかそれっぽく
グチャグチャっと書いとくか》
ありがとう！へぇ～｡
Thanks!
You're the first person to get my autograph.
かくとく
君が俺のサイン獲得第１号だよ｡
ウッフッフ…｡
I'm never using that one again, though.
《２度と書けねえけど それ》
This is crazy...
《なんてこった…》
《ブルースーツを着てるだけで
こういうことになるのか…》
I put on my blue jumpsuit, and I'm already getting special treatment.
《みんな すげえ見てるし…》
Everyone's looking at me.
(ケンジ)ムッ君！
Mu!
ああっ ケンジ！
《やっと来た！》
Oh, Kenji!
Someone's finally here.
(小町)なんやえらい はりきってる
やんかぁ ムッちゃん！
You must be really excited, Mu!
おおお～ みなさん！
Oh, everyone's here...
(新田)なんで今 ブルースーツ
着てんだよ 南波｡
Why are you in your jumpsuit, Nanba?
え!?いやだって
むらさき
昨日 紫さんからメールで…｡
Huh?
Didn't you see Murasaki's e-mail?
"Change into your blue jumpsuit as soon as you arrive at the airport tomorrow!
That's what all the astronauts do!
I'll be wearing mine when I leave home.
｢…俺なんて 自宅から
すでに着て行くからね➡
じゃあ また明日！｣｡
See ya tomorrow, then."
Yo! Looks like everyone's here.
(紫)やぁ！みんな揃ったね！
じゃあ 行こうか！ウフ！
Let's take off, then.
う～ん…うんうん…う～ん｡
プフッ！うふふふ…！
《いたずラッコめ～…》
Damned prankster...
I just checked with Murasaki.
さっき 紫さんに聞いたらさ
僕とムッ君だけだってさ｡
He only sent the jumpsuit e-mail to you and me.
ブルースーツ着用のメール
送ったのって｡
え!?ケンジも
あのメール 来てたの？
Wait, he sent you that e-mail?
Yeah.
《じゃあ 何でテメエは
ブルースーツ着てねえんだよ》
Then why didn't you wear your jumpsuit?
ムッ君は 最後まで
見なかったんだね メール｡
You didn't see the last part of his e-mail, did you?
Hmm?
この本文の ず～っと下まで
スクロールしていくとさ➡
If you keep scrolling down...
見てて｡
Look.
(メール:紫の声)｢ウソピョン｣｡
J/K!
J... K?
《ウソ…ピョン!?》
ホ ホントだ｡俺のも…｡
Y-You're right... It's there.
このメールを どうとるべきか
迷ったけど僕なりに考えた結果…｡
I wasn't sure how to interpret this e-mail,
but after some thinking,
｢最後まで見落とさず確認しろ｣
すなわち ｢常に注意深く➡
I'm guessing he wanted us to read the message all the way through.
Warning us to be sure to always pay attention to each little detail.
いまし
物事を観察すべし｣という戒めと➡
He wasn't saying that we should actually wear our jumpsuits,
｢ブルースーツを着てくる
必要まではないが➡
着ている気持ちでいろ｣
そして｢候補生としての➡
but that we should behave as if we were.
自覚を忘れるな｣っていう
僕らのやる気を促すために➡
So we remember our responsibilities as astronaut candidates.
紫さんが考えた 先輩からの
メッセージなんじゃないかと➡
He meant this as a veteran's words of wisdom.
僕は思うんだよ｡
Or that's what I think.
《そんな深い意味ね～よ！》
You're giving him too much credit.
ムッちゃん ケンちゃん
マシュマロいるか？マシュマロ｡
Mu, Ken...
Want some marshmallows?
Help yourself.
遠慮せんと食べ｡
４個ぐらい取りぃ｡
Take four or so.
あ…ああ どうも｡
いただきます｡
Th-Thanks...
Don't mind if I do.
ああ あとな 黒酢あんねん｡
ミラクル黒酢｡
Ah, right...
I have black vinegar.
Miracle Black Vinegar.
ええでぇ～ これ｡飲むか？
細胞 活性化するらしいわ｡
This is good stuff...
Want some?
It helps stimulate your cells.
Just look at me.
おかげさんで ほれっ｡
ほっぺたプリプリのフクフクや｡
It's why my cheeks are so firm.
Like marshmallows!
マシュマロや マシュマロ｡
触ってみるか？
Wanna touch?
Huh?
(小町)触ってみぃ ほれ｡
い いや…｡
Give it a try...
No thanks.
(小町)ええから 遠慮せんと
ツンツンツンて➡
Don't worry... Just poke, poke, poke.
Go ahead.
３回くらいやってみて｡
やってみぃって…｡
Er...
This is one of the tricks to having more free time for yourself.
(ビンス)人生に余裕を持たせる
コツの１つですよ｡➡
車を飛ばすこと｡
Pedal to the metal.
ボ…ボールド先輩
ここまで飛ばさなくても…｡
B-Bold...
We're not in that much of a hurry.
《た 頼むから事故るなよ
やっとの思いで➡
P-Please don't get in an accident...
I finally became an astronaut candidate.
宇宙飛行士候補生にまで
なったんだぞ》
フッ 何をふぬけたことを…
もっと飛ばしますよ｡
Don't be such a wuss.
I'm speeding up.
《移動時間ほどムダなものはない｡
人生は短いんだ》
Travel is the biggest waste of time.
Life is short.
(ビンス)ほら もう着いた｡
Okay, we're here.
(ビンス)じゃ 私はこれで｡
I need to get going.
大丈夫か？
ちくしょう…➡
Are you okay?
Damn...
何なんだ あの人｡
What's his problem?
(ラリー)ビンス！➡
Vince!
ハンッ ま～た恒例の
新人ドライブか？
Taking rookies on a drive again?
ええ あの２人は大した事
ありませんでした｡➡
Yes, those two failed to impress me.
やはり万年学生の
はかせ
博士研究員出身の子は➡
After all that time devoted to research, these university boys are too weak.
ヤワで困ります｡
将来彼らと同じロケットに
乗る羽目になったら➡
If I ever have to ride on the same rocket as them,
私は辞退するでしょうね｡
I'll probably retire.
それよりビンス
バトラー室長が呼んで…｡
室長が呼んでましたか｡➡
Anyway, Vince...
Chief Butler is...
The chief wants to see me?
ＯＫ ＯＫ
ちょうど向かうところです｡
Okay, okay.
I was on my way over.
ああ そうだ ビンス
今晩さ ヒマだったら…｡
ＯＫ｡➡
Right, Vince. About tonight...
Okay.
Sherlock's, at 7 PM.
１９時にシャーロックスで｡
NASA Astronaut
Vincent Bold
≪バトラー室長
ﾋﾞﾝｾﾝﾄ･ﾎﾞｰﾙﾄﾞです｡失礼します≫
Chief Butler, it's Vincent Bold.
(バトラー)来たか ボールド君
入りたまえ｡
You're here, Bold? Come in.
もう入ってます｡
I'm already inside.
Oh.
今回 君とラリー君に
宇宙飛行士候補生の➡
NASA Astronaut Office Chief
Jason Butler
I plan to assign you and Larry as
training instructors this time around.
訓練教官を任せようと思ってね｡
ＯＫです
話は だいたい聞いています｡
Okay, I have all the information I need.
すでに名簿ファイルも
まとめてあります｡
And I already have a roster prepared.
さすが仕事が早いなぁ
ボールド君｡➡
You always do move fast, Bold...
So this year, we have...
それで
今回の新人ってのは何名…｡
今回の候補生➡
There are a total of thirty candidates.
アスキャンは計３０名｡
アメリカ１０名 日本５名➡
Ten Americans, five Japanese,
イギリス ドイツが４名ずつ
カナダ イタリア フランスが➡
four British and Dutch, two Canadians, Italians, and French, and one Indian.
２名ずつ インドから１名
うち 女性は７名です｡
Seven are female.
なるほど｡
I see...
《また聞く前に
言っちゃうよ この人》
He always answers before I can even ask a question.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)じゃあまぁ よろしく
頼むよ ボールド君｡
(ﾋﾞﾝｽ)はい｡了解です｡
Well, I'm counting on you, Bold.
Yes, roger that.
《かぶせてくるなぁ～》
He always interrupts me...
ところで ボールド君…｡
(ビンス)では 失礼します｡
By the way, Bold...
Then I'll excuse myself.
せっかち野郎…ナンバーワン｡
Number one restless guy...
おはよう ビンスさ…｡
おはよう｡
Good morning, Vince.
Good morning.
おはようございます ビンスさん｡
おはよう｡
Good morning, Vince.
Good morning.
(ビンス)《こいつがヒビトの
兄貴か…》
This is Hibito's older brother?
《ふぬけた顔をしてる
当然 軍隊経験もなし｡➡
He looks rather dim.
Naturally, he has no military experience.
おく
弟に後れをとっている上に
この締まりのない｢ふぬけ顔｣…➡
He's a step behind his little brother, and he looks like a fool.
It's clear that he's a lost cause.
救いようのない
ノロマだとすぐ分かる｡➡
ヤワな連中が多くて困る｡➡
It's difficult with so many weak candidates.
If I have to ride on the same rocket as any of these, I may have to retire.
将来 同じロケットに乗る羽目に
なったら 辞退せざるを得ないな》
Since I've been selected as a training instructor,
《私が訓練教官に選ばれた以上➡
I must employ my training as a soldier.
元軍人として
半端な訓練では終わらせない》
《軍隊式で いかせてもらう》
I'll give them the military treatment.
We're here!
着いたでぇ～！
テキサス州ヒューストンやでぇ！
Houston, Texas!
なんやムッちゃん
めっちゃ張り切ってるやんか！
Mu, you're totally stylin'...
Yep.
In that case, I'll try to stand out as much as possible.
《ここまで来たら
目立ったもん勝ち！》
どう見ても変な奴だぜ
ジャクサ
ＪＡＸＡの恥｡
You look like a total weirdo.
You're embarrassing JAXA.
ふふっ 新田…｡
Nitta.
You're just jealous...
《本当はうらやましいくせに》
じゃ 俺は急いでスペｰスセンタｰに
行かなきゃなんないんで➡
Well, I should head over to the space center.
あとは小町っちゃん ヨロシク！
Koma, you take it from here.
(小町)ＯＫ！まかしとき！
(ケンジ)お気をつけて！
Okay, I've got this.
Have a safe trip.
Okay, everyone.
(小町)ほな皆さん 今日はこのまま
ホテルで休んで➡
We'll stay at a hotel today.
Tomorrow, we'll begin looking for housing.
明日からは各自の部屋探しやで｡
私が 不動産屋 案内したるわ｡➡
I'll take you to see the realtors.
１０日後から
訓練が始まるからな｡➡
Training begins in ten days.
You'll need a place to live before then.
それまでに住むとこ
見つけなあかんでぇ｡
オジー！
Ozzy!
(ケンジ)おおっ 広いね～！
This is a big place...
悪いね ムッ君 僕まで｡
ホントに泊まっていいの？
Sorry for imposing, Mu.
Is it really okay for me to stay here?
気にすんな｡１部屋空いてんだ｡
Don't worry about it. There's an empty room.
ここの住人は今 月面にいるしな｡
Since its occupant is on the moon right now.
[TV]男の魅力だよ
いま見せてやる｡
Time to use that manly charm.
[TV]やあ 調子どう？
Hey, how you doin'?
How are you?
[TV]あんたは？
Terrible... No luck with women.
[TV]ダメだね さっぱりモテない｡
[TV](笑い)
What happened to using charm?
[TV]魅力が聞いて呆れるよ｡
[TV](笑い)
Hey, Mu...
なあ ムッ君｡
Hmm?
紫さんから
意外なこと 聞いたんだよ｡
Murasaki asked me an odd question.
へぇ…何？何!?
Huh? What? What?
(ケンジ)毎回 この２年間の
訓練中にさ…➡
Every time they hold this two-year training program...
いや…やっぱいいや｡ごめん｡
No, never mind...
Sorry.
Huh?
なんだよ？
What was that about?
The stones out in the fields
are worn down by their daily existence and disappear
That's their trial
When will we be able to resist fate?
Before you lose all hope
and say that we can't win against gravity
go without stopping
past the goal line
You have such strong convictions
Leave your footprints on this Earth
Maybe their tiny length will cause a miracle in the end
Give us a magnificent jump
Run now and do it
Jump past all you see overhead
This is your stride
(ケンジ)＜なあ ムッ君｡毎回
この２年間の訓練中にさ…｡➡
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#47 The First Promise
Hey, Mu...
Every time they hold this two-year training program...
あ…やっぱいいや｡ごめん＞
No, never mind...
Sorry.
＜えっ!?何？それ！
でも 分かってる分かってる｡➡
Huh? What was that about?
But I understand.
そうまで言われて しつこく
聞くほど 俺はヤボじゃねえよ＞
I'm sensitive enough to know I shouldn't pursue the matter.
＜フッフッフ｡
ケンジには もう聞かねえ｡➡
I won't ask Kenji.
紫さんに聞こう！＞
I'll ask Murasaki!
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"The First Promise"
Y'know, astronauts are kind of like stage actors...
＜宇宙飛行士ってのは あれだ…
舞台役者に似てんだよな＞
ひびと
(南波日々人)パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
How is the pie?
This week's space photo!
今週の宇宙写真で～す！
ウヒョー！
Whee!